<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SelFit</string>

    //Abs Workout
    <string name="incline_procedure">Start in regular push-up position but with your hands elevated on a chair or a bench.\n\nThen push your body up down using your arm strength.\n\nRemember to keep your body straight.</string>
    <string name="sit_up">Lie on your back with your ears. \n\nThen Lift your upper bodey off the floor and slowly up to the sitting position. Dont tug your neck when you get up. \n\nSlowly go back to the start position and repeat the exercise. \n\nIf your spine hurts, please change another workout.</string>
    <string name="mountain_climber">Start in the push-up position. Bend your right knee towards your chest and keep your left leg straight, then quickly switch from one leg to the other. \n\nThis exercise strengthens multiple muscle groups.</string>
    <string name="abdominal_crunches">Lie on your back with your knees bent and your arms stretch forward. \n\nThen lift your body off the floor. Hold for few seconds and slowly return. \n\n It primarily works the rectus abdominis muscle and the obliques</string>
    <string name="russian_twist">Sit with bent knees and your feet pressing firmly into the floor, holding your hands next to your chest. Sit back slightly, keeping your spine straight. \n\nExhale as you twist to the left, punching your right arm over to the left side. Inhale back to center, and then do the opposite side.</string>
    <string name="heel_touch">Lie on the ground with your legs bent and your arms by your sides. \n\nSlightly lif your upper body off the floor and make your hands alternately reach your heels. </string>
    <string name="side_bridges">Start by lying on your left side with your weight on your elbow. \n\nExhale, pull your abs to your spine, and lift your pelvis off the floor, coming into a side elbow-plank. \n\nHold for three seconds.\nDo two to three sets of 12 reps on each side.</string>
    <string name="bicycle_crunches">Lie on the floor with your hands behind your ears. \n\nRaise your knees and close your right elbow toward your right knee. Repeat the exercise.</string>
    <string name="plank">Lay on the floor with your elbows under your shoulders, hands flat on the floor and core engaged. \n\nKeeping your forearms and knees on the floor slowly raise yourself upwards until your body is in a straight line from your knees to your head. Hold the position for as long as you can.</string>
    <string name="abs_up">Lie on your back with your arms and legs extended and your legs squeezed together \n\nRaise your upper body and legs, use your arms to touch your toes, then go back to the start position and repeat exercise.</string>
    <string name="leg_raises">Lie down on your back, and put your hands beneath your hips for support. \n\nThen lift your legs up until they form a right angle with the floor. \n\nSlowly bring your legs back down and repeat exercise.</string>

    //Chest Workout
    <string name="dynamic_chest">Start by standing up straight with your arms at your side and feet shoulder width apart. \n\nExtend your hands out in front of your palms together then quickly move your arms back as far as possible. \n\nReturn back to the starting position quickly and repeat for as man reps and sets as desired.</string>
    <string name="push_up">Lay prone on the ground with arms supporting your body. \n\nKeep your body straight while raising and lowering your body with arms.</string>
    <string name="incline_push_up">Start in the regular push-up position but with your hands elevated on a chair or bench. \n\nThen push your body up down using your arm strength. \n\nRemember to keep your body straight.</string>
    <string name="hindu_push_up">Start with your hands and feet touching the floor, body bent and butt up in an upside down ‘V’ shape. Then bend your elbows to bring your body towards the floor. \n\n3. When your body is close to the floor, raise your upper body as far as possible. Then return to the original position and repeat.</string>
    <string name="cobra_stretch">Lie down on your stomach and bend your elbows with your hands beneath your shoulders. \n\nThen push your chest up off the ground as far as possible. Hold this position for second.</string>
    <string name="knee_push_up">Start in regular push-up position, then let your knees touch the floor and raise your feet up off the floor. \n\nNext push your body up and down.</string>
    <string name="lunge_knee_hops">Stand with your feet shoulder width apart. Step your left leg back. Lower your body until your right thigh is parallel to the floor. \n\nPush through your front heel to come up, and raise your left knee as high as you can at the same time. Make sure your front knee does not go over your toes. \n\nIn hale as you go down and exhale as you go up.</string>
    <string name="chest_press_pulse">Lie on a flat bench with your feet pressing into the floor. Draw your shoulders down and back to press them into the bench. Hold two dumbbells with palms facing forward and your thumbs wrapped around the handle. \n\nOn an inhale, lower the dumbbells slightly wider than your mid-chest, slowly and with control. Gently touch the dumbbells to your chest. \n\nOn an exhale, press your arms upwards, keeping your elbows slightly bent. Position the dumbbells just below eye level. \n4. Do 2 to 3 sets of 8 to 15 repetitions.</string>
    <string name="staggered_push_up">Start in the regular push-up position, but with one hand in front of the other.Then do a push-up and switch the other hand in front. \n\nRemember to keep your body straight.</string>
    <string name="wall_push_up">While facing the wall, stand just over one arms length away. For most people, a comfortable stance will probably be between 12 to 18 inches (30 to 45 centimeters) away from the wall.[2] \n\nYour body should create a 45-degree angle when you place your hands against the wall.[3] \n\nKeep your feet shoulder-width apart. Put the palms of both hands flat against the wall at shoulder height, approximately shoulder-width apart.</string>

    //Arm Workout
    <string name="shoulder_stretch">Relax your shoulders. Raise one arm to shoulder height, and reach it across your chest. \n\nPull the arm slightly toward you with your other arm. This will help you get a gentle stretch. Hold for about 6 seconds. \nRepeat 2 to 4 times.</string>
    <string name="arm_raises">Stand with feet shoulder length apart and keep your hands at your side with palms facing forward, raise your arms up and out to the sides so that your arms are at shoulder height. \n\nThen lower them to starting position, with a fluid and constant motion until you have completed the set.</string>
    <string name="side_arm_raise">Keep feet pointed straight ahead. Raise both arms, to the side of the body to shoulder level. \n\nKeep shoulder blades retracted and depressed throughout the exercise. Do not allow the low-back to arch. \nHold. Return arms slowly back to the side of the body and repeat.</string>
    <string name="arm_circles">Stand on the floor with your arms extended straight out to the sides at shoulder height. Move your arms clockwise in circles fast. \n\nTry to do it as fast as you can. \nIt’s a great exercise for the deltoid muscle.</string>
    <string name="floor_tricep_dips">Sit on the floor with your knees bent and feet flat on the floor. Put your hands beneath your shoulders with your fingers pointing toward your hips. \n\nLift your hips off the floor. Then bend and extend your elbows to lower and lift your hips. \n\nRepeat the exercise to strengthen your upper arms.</string>
    <string name="punches">Stand with feet slightly wider than shoulder distance apart and bend knees slightly. Tighten the core to keep your center still. \n\nPunch out one arm at a time at a steady pace.</string>
    <string name="triceps_stretch">Put your left hand on your back, use your right hand to grab your left elbow and gently pull it. \n\nHold this position for a few seconds.</string>
    <string name="arm_crunch">Lie in your left side with your knees bent and lifted. Grasp your left thigh with your left hand and put your right hand behind your head. \n\nThen raise your upper body by pulling your left thigh. Repeat the exercise.</string>
    <string name="prone_triceps">Lie on your stomach with your hands underneath your shoulders and your elbows bone. Slightly raise your chest up. Exhale on the way up, and inhale on the way down. \n\nSqueeze your triceps when pushing your chest up. Constantly keep tension on your arms and don’t completely relax on the mat during exercise.</string>
    <string name="reverse_snow_angels">Lie on your stomach with your arms at your sides and palms facing down. Lift your arms and move them to touch your thumbs over your head. \nnReturn and repeat. \n\nBreathe naturally. Please keep a controlled movement. Don’t let your arms touch the ground during exercise. Keep your neck neutral.</string>

    //Leg Workout
    <string name="lunge">Stand with your feet shoulder width apart and your hands on your lips. \n\nTake step forward with your right leg and lower your body until your right thigh is parallel with floor \n\nThen return and switch to the other leg. This exercise strengthens the quadriceps, gluteus maximus and hamstring.</string>
    <string name="side_lunge">Bend your knees to approximately 90 degrees as you lower yourself. Remember to keep your trunk upright and core engaged. Then, forcefully push off from your front leg to return to the starting position. \n\nRelease the position by pushing off your left foot to return to the starting position. \n\nPerform one set of side lunges on your left leg, then switch to your right leg.</string>
    <string name="curtsy_lunges">Bend your knees and lower your hips until your left thigh is nearly parallel to the floor. \n\nKeep your torso upright and your hips and shoulders as square as possible to the wall in front of you. Return to start. Then repeat on the other side.</string>
    <string name="adductor_stretch">Stand tall with your chest up and your core tight. Your feet should be shoulder width apart. \n\nStep directly to the left, leaving your right foot in place. Bend the left knee and pause once the upper left thigh is parallel to the ground. \n\nHold this stretch for 20 to 40 seconds.</string>
    <string name="side_circles">Lie on your right side with your head resting on your hand. Lift your left leg and rotate it in circles. \n\nMake sure your body stays straight. Keep your left leg directly over your body. Breathe regularly.</string>
    <string name="spine_lumbar">Lie your back on the floor. Cross one leg over the other while twisting your hips and spine. \n\nKeep your opposite arm stretch. You could hold on your knee to make the stretch stronger if you feel comfortable.</string>
    <string name="bottom_lift">Lie on your right side while head resting on your hand. Put your left foot forward on the floor. \n\nLift your right leg up and down. Exhale while lifting your leg and inhale while lowering it. Keep your upper body still. Keep your core tight. \n\nRepeat it on the left side.</string>
    <string name="quad_stretch">Stand with your right hand on the wall. Bend your left leg and grasp your ankle or toes to bring your left calf close to your left thigh. Hold this position. \n\nRepeat it on the right side.</string>
    <string name="frog_press">Lie on your back with your knees bent to 90 degrees, turning them outwards like a frog. Make sure to keep your heels pressed together while flexing your feet towards you. \n\nTighten your stomach and crunch up, lifting your head and shoulders off the floor, holding this position.</string>
    <string name="lunge_hops">Stand with your feet shoulder width apart. Step your left leg back. Lower your body until your right thigh is parallel to the floor. \n\nPush through your front heel to come up, and raise your left knee as high as you can at the same time. Make sure your front knee doesn’t go over your toes. \n\nInhale as you go down, and exhale as you go up.</string>


</resources>
